Oliver White

6872 Notre-Dame Street Orléans, Ontario, K1C1H7 (613)-408-1771 oliverwhite93@gmail.com

Software Developer with 5 years of experience leading and contributing to a wide variety of projects. Have a degree in Computer Engineering with a specialization in Software Engineering. Experienced with different fields from computer hardware to cloud-based software design as well as Artificial Intelligence and multi-agent systems.

Professional Experience

Fullscript

JavaScript Developer II, July 2022 – Current

Ottawa, Ontario

- Built an address validation service saving 100k/year in failed deliveries and support costs.
- Improved checkout loading speed and performance by 100%.
- Improved checkout conversion through optimizing user experience with a data driven approach.
- Rebuilt prescription feature, modernizing UI and unifying look between native app and web app.

Welbi Technologies Inc.

Software Developer, January 2019 – July 2022

Ottawa, Ontario

- Designed and implemented a typescript RESTful API using TypeScript and Express to provide support for recreation and administration staff in retirement communities across the country.
- Lead the design and implementation of core systems, everything from authentication to customizable surveys and everything in between.
- Collaborated with third party vendors to allow real time data synchronization and reporting between systems, leading to increased client revenue and unlocking sales to many potential clients and scaling our client base by over 200%.
- Built a real time data driven analytics system and data aggregation tools using GraphQL and NextJS with end-to-end typing.

Louisville Geek LLC

Full Stack Web Developer, February 2017 - December 2018 Remote in Granada, Spain

- Designed and built a mobile form designer for aggregating data on the safety of critical energy infrastructure, resulting in greatly improved on-site efficiency for the client.
- Built a native android application to scan, verify and gather data from thousands of different identity documents that is used by a major automobile rental agency.

• Designed and built a task tracker for one of the largest airport service providers that is used across the US in multiple major airline hubs.

Education

<u>University of Granada</u> Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering, July 2017 Granada, Spain

Skills

- Typescript, JavaScript, PHP, Java, Python.
- MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Bilingual in English and Spanish.